## Vic Cekvenich

<u>vic@eml.cc</u> https://cekvenich.github.io/cekvenich

### VP Engineering / Director / Manager

### **Summary**:

'I code and manage people smarter than me'. Seasoned technology leader with experience in remote development, team building, innovation, back end and full-stack development. I love coding and this is an influence on the team. At the beginning of my career, I worked on DB performance optimization, then startups and networks. Some highlights over the years include working at NASA, mastering SQL performance under load, publishing an early book on Java. I also won trainer of the year by JDJ. The experience I have helps with perspective. I am proud to be a scalability/web expert. I have experience in managing an offshore team of up to 120 members, organizing and conducting meetings for project requirements and status discussions. On a personal note: I did a few 'Olympic' triathlons and I contribute and maintain open-source projects.

<u>Some of the tech I use:</u> SQL, Java, Netty, Node.js, VLDB, SEO, HTML5, S3, NoSQL(Mongo) Pug, CSS, APIs, Data visualization, Linux, Markdown, Mobile/Hybrid, JAMstack.org, Architecture, Custom Elements, Cordova, Kafka, Docker, Agile, CMS, Distributed/Network Computing, Video, remote development.

Personal web page with projects: https://cekvenich.github.io/cekvenich

# **Professional Experience**

- **MetaBake.net LLC**, FL (Jan. 2017 Present): *Vice President Of Engineering*MetaBake LLC is freelance remote development shop specializing in low-cost low-code development. Consulting, custom development and training- solutions that are maintainable and future safe. Project include a market-product-fit 'survey' (I wrote the prototype and hired the offshore team).
  - Hands on tech-lead software development
  - Responsible for project delivery and hiring
  - My team of 7 remote developers were responsible for developing, managing and maintaining multiple full stack applications/services interacting with our customers, vendors and other partners.
  - Facilitate weekly sprints with the the team.

- Working with team and business/product owners to deliver the solutions on time.
- **Apakau**, *CA(Oct. 2012 Dec 2016): Principal Engineer/Founder/CTO*Eliminates the possibility of DDoS attacks to dynamic APIs via globally deployed Cloud Proxies that intercept HTTP request and accelerate traffic under load without caching, using QOS priority. Tech: Security from DDOS, Java, Node, Kafka, Architecture, Network/REST/HTTP, Dashboard, HTML5 tech/CSS. (I wrote the prototype in Java and hired a local team).
  - Hands on Java tech-lead software development
  - Responsible for project delivery and hiring
  - My team of 11 developers were responsible for developing, managing and maintaining multiple full stack applications/services interacting with our customers, vendors and other partners.
  - Facilitate weekly sprints with the the team.
- Rocket Ninja, CA(Jun 2011 Sept. 2012): VP Engineering

A gaming company working on e-cards, 3D chat and related. Upgraded development process and skills, for example splitting up front end and back end code. This dramatically improved the competitiveness of the company. Tech: Architecture, Java, ActionScript, HTML5 tech.

- Second level manager
- Responsible for project delivery and hiring
- My team of 30 developers were responsible for developing, managing and maintaining multiple full stack applications/services interacting with our customers, vendors and other partners.
- Working with team and business/product owners to deliver the solutions on time.
- Akamai, CA(Jun 2010 Jun 2011): Sr. Software Engineer

Developed video media libraries that are used by professional services and Akamai clients to make efficient and secure media players. Majority of media companies are Akamai customers, including events, like streaming China Olympics. Worked on the key engineering team for streaming. Tech: ActionScript, Java, Architecture, HTML5 tech. One of the projects is open source video player OVP, also DRM, UDP/p2p.

- **Tivo**, *CA*(*Aug 2009 Jun 2010*): *Sr. Software Engineer*Next generation embedded consumer product w/ RIA, media content, 3D and social networking. Tech: Embedded device, ActionScript, Java– ex: 'Tivo TV grid'.
- PhoneZoo, CA(Oct 2007- Aug 2009): Architect;

PhoneZoo was the dominant mobile teen social networking site. Action-Script, JavaScript, Java and JSP development for a web site catering to a teen social network. Tech: HTML5, Developed widgets, using Java services.

- **Vendio** (Nov 2006 Oct 2007): CTO; Vendio is eBay's largest partner. Leveraged remote development.
- **Keibi** (Feb 2006 Nov 2006): VP Engineering/Co-founder; A start up that would predict bad behavior on social networks to help improve Ad rates.
- baseBeans Engineering (Apr 2001 Jan 2006): Principal Software Engineer; One project was for Ziff-Davis, a gaming social network
- **Novell/SilverStream** (May 1999 April 2001): Sr. Application Engineer; One project was 'Re-engineering the corporation', NASA
- **SEI** TX (1996-99): Instructor; I did vendor certified training in 12 front end and back end public and private courses.
- Computer Science Corporation, TX (1993-95): Sr. Architect; One project was
- Omnicom/Rapp, NYC(1990-1994): MIS; DB Marketing, dBase, SQL

#### **Education & Credentials**

- CUNY Queens College 1990, Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, NYC
- Other:
  - Java 2020: https://github.com/intuition-dev/SNX/blob/master/docs/2020short.md
  - First book on MVC / Java Struts @2001 open sourced ( <a href="http://cekvenich.github.io/cekvenich/book.pdf">http://cekvenich.github.io/cekvenich/book.pdf</a> )
  - Won Trainer of the Year, by IDI
  - Personal web page with projects: https://cekvenich.github.io/cekvenich